import 'package:quiz_app_tutorial/models/question.dart';

const List<Question> questions = [
  Question(
    question: '1. What is the capital of France?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Madrid',
      'b) Paris',
      'c) Berlin',
      'd) Rome',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '2. In what continent is Brazil located?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Europe',
      'b) Asia',
      'c) North America',
      'd) South America',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '3. What is the largest continent in the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) North America',
      'b) Africa',
      'c) Asia',
      'd) South America',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '4. What is the capital city of Australia?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Sydney',
      'b) Melbourne',
      'c) Brisbane',
      'd) Canberra',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '5. Which of these countries is an island nation?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Italy',
      'b) United Kingdom',
      'c) Japan',
      'd) France',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '6. Which of these countries is located in South America?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Spain',
      'b) Germany',
      'c) Brazil',
      'd) Canada',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '7. Which is the largest ocean in the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Pacific Ocean',
      'b) Atlantic Ocean',
      'c) Indian Ocean',
      'd) Artic Ocean',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '8. What is the name of the largest desert in the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Gobi Desert',
      'b) Sahara Desert',
      'c) Antartica',
      'd) Atacama Desert',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '9. What is the name of the country knows as the "Land of the Rising Sun"?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) China',
      'b) South Korea',
      'c) Vietnam',
      'd) Japan',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '10. What phenomenon made the dinosaurs go extinct?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Meteor Strike',
      'b) Global Warming',
      'c) Death',
      'd) Ice Age',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '11. What is the shape of the sun?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Spherical',
      'b) Round',
      'c) Oval',
      'd) Circle',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '12. What is the tallest mountain in Africa?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Killimanjaro',
      'b) Fako',
      'c) Everest',
      'd) Speke',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '13. What is the largest planet in our solar system?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Earth',
      'b) Jupiter',
      'c) Saturn',
      'd) Venus',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '14. What is the longest river in the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Nile',
      'b) Amazon',
      'c) Mississippi',
      'd) Danube',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '15. What is the smallest planet in our solar system?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Venus',
      'b) Mars',
      'c) Earth',
      'd) Mercury',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '16. What is the highest mountain in the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Mont Blanc',
      'b) Everest',
      'c) Kilimanjaro',
      'd) Aconcagua',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '17.What is the flattest Country in the earth?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Nigeria ',
      'b) Gambia',
      'c) Maldeeves',
      'd) Netherlands',
    ],
  ), Question(
    question: '18. Upper Volta is the old name of?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Cape Verde',
      'b) Burkina Faso',
      'c) Angola',
      'd) Denmark',
    ],
  ),
   Question(
    question: '19. Who constructed the Suez Canal?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Fyodor Litke',
      'b) Pyotr Semyonov-Tyan-Shansky',
      'c) Voin Rimsky-Korsakov',
      'd) Ferdinand de Lesseps',
    ],
  ),
   Question(
    question: '20. How many days does the moon take to revolve round the Earth?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) 365 days',
      'b) 1 day(s)',
      'c) 29.5 days',
      'd) 27.3 days ',
    ],
  ),
];
